Walk down the right back alley in Sin City and you can find anything...
Sin City is a crime, thriller film directed by Robert Rodriguez.
Welcome to Sin City.
This town beckons to the tough, the corrupt, the brokenhearted.
Some call it dark… Hard-boiled.
Then there are those who call it home — Crooked
cops, sexy dames, desperate vigilantes.
Some are seeking revenge, others lust after redemption, and
then there are those hoping for a little of both.
A universe of unlikely and reluctant heroes still trying to do
the right thing in a city that refuses to care.
Hartigan, played by Bruce Willis.
Nancy, played by Jessica Alba.
Dwight, played by Clive Owen.
Marv, played by Mickey Rourke.
Cardinal Roark, played by Rutger Hauer.
Jackie Boy, played by Benicio del Toro.
Sin City (also known as Frank Miller's Sin City) is a 2005 American neo-noir crime anthology film directed
by Robert Rodriguez and Frank Miller based on Miller's comic book series of the same name.
The film stars an ensemble cast led by Jessica Alba, Benicio del Toro, Brittany Murphy, Clive Owen, Mickey Rourke, Bruce Willis, and Elijah Wood, and featuring Alexis Bledel,
Powers Boothe, Michael Clarke Duncan, Rosario Dawson, Devon Aoki, Carla Gugino, Rutger Hauer, Jaime King, Michael Madsen, Nick Stahl, and Makenzie Vega among others.
Much of the film is based on the first, third, and fourth
books in Miller's original comic series.
The Hard Goodbye is about an ex-convict who embarks on a rampage
in search of his one-time sweetheart's killer.
The Big Fat Kill follows a private investigator who gets caught in a street war between a
group of prostitutes and a group of mercenaries, the police, and the mob.
That Yellow Bastard focuses on an aging police officer who protects a
young woman from a grotesquely disfigured serial killer.
The intro and outro of the film are based on the short story "The Customer is Always Right",
which is collected in Booze, Broads & Bullets, the sixth book in the comic series.
Sin City premiered at the Mann National Theater on March 28, 2005
and was released by Miramax Films on April 1, 2005.
The film was a critical and commercial success, gathering particular recognition for the film's unique color processing which rendered most of the film
in black and white while retaining or adding color for selected objects, while grossing $158.7 million against a $40 million budget.
The film was screened at the 2005 Cannes Film Festival in competition and won
the Technical Grand Prize for the film's "visual shaping".
A sequel also directed by Miller and Rodriguez was released in 2014, Sin City: A
Dame to Kill For, but failed to match the success of its predecessor.
The film explores themes of dystopia, based on comic,
anthology, black and white, held captive.
The tone is dark and intense.